# Riyan Shaikh

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

riyanshaikh78@gmail.com

9637060243

Pune Maharashtra,India

https://www.linkedin.com/in/riyan-shaikh- in 391108210/

#### **SUMMARY**

With 2.2+ years of experience in .Net development, I am proficient in C#, ASP.Net MVC, ASP.Net Core Web API, Angular, and JavaScript. I have a strong grasp of OOP and SDLC life cycle, making me a quick learner, problem solver, and creative thinker. I also have basic knowledge of cloud technologies like Azure and AWS. My work experience in .Net development has honed my skills, and I am ready to take on new challenges.

# **SKILLS**

ASP.Net Core	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$	SQL Server	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$
ASP.Net MVC 5	••••	JavaScript/Jquery	••••
ASP.Net Web API		Angular 13	••••
Core Java	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$	React JS	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$
C/C++	$\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$	HTML/CSS	••••

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Software Developer

Cloud9 e-biz Pvt. Ltd Jun 2023 - Present Resource Planning Domain, Project ERP.

- Enhanced ERP Software: Project Section.
- Developed functionalities to create, edit, and delete projects and specific menus.
- Performed CRUD operations on Web API for seamless data management.
- Associated milestones with tasks, deadlines, and team members for streamlined project workflows.
- · Worked on stored procedures in SQL Server that accept input in XML format and return data.

Technologies: ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Core Web API, Angular 13, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, SQL Server, Postman, TFS

## Jr.Software Developer

Security Shell Infotech PVT LTD Mar 2022 - Mar 2023

Security and Safety Domain, Project ISecure.

- Developed modules for Employee Engagement using ASP.Net Core MVC, ensuring seamless functionality and user-centered design.
- Created optimized database tables using DB First Approach, enhancing data storage and retrieval efficiency.
- Implemented advanced CRUD operations with C# and Entity Framework ORM, improving data interaction performance.
- Monitored and resolved failed queries on SQL Server.
- Wrote test cases in ASP.Net Core for user authentication and coded them.

Technologies: ASP.Net Core MVC, ASP.Net MVC 5, ASP.Net Web API, Entity Framework, React JS, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, SQL Server, Postman, Git

# **PROJECTS**

## **ERP (Enterprise Resource Planning)**

Developer Jun 2023 - Present

Worked at Cloud9 e-biz Pvt. Ltd.

**Description:** 

Enhanced ERP software with new project management features and functionalities.

**Project Milestone Menu:** 

- Introduced a new "Project Milestone" menu for efficient project tracking.
- Enabled users to create, edit, and delete project milestones.
- Associated milestones with tasks, deadlines, and team members for streamlined project workflows.

#### Sales Plan Menu:

- Introduced a new "Sales Plan" menu within the ERP system for efficient sales strategizing and planning.
- Enabled sales managers to define targets, set revenue goals, and allocate resources for sales campaigns.

Technologies: ASP.Net Core MVC, ASP.Net MVC, Angular 13, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, SQL Server, Postman.

#### **ISecure**

Developer Mar 2022 - Mar 2023

Worked at Security Shell Infotech.

# Description:

Asp.Net MVC web application designed to handle access, visitors, parking, locker, and attendance through HID Controllers.

#### Attendance module:

- Keeping attendance of employees based on transactions using HID controllers.
- Leave request approval.
- Comp-off approval.
- Shift management.
- Overtime management.

#### **Access Control Modules:**

- Live transaction detection.
- Old transaction reports generation in PDF as well as Excel.

Technologies: ASP.Net Core MVC, ASP.Net Web API, ReactJS, Entity Framework, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, SQL Server, Postman.

### **EDUCATION**

## **BBA(Computer Application)**

Abeda Inamdar Senior College of Art Science and Commerce Pune *Jul 2019 - Apr 2022* Note: In 2015, Pune University changed BCA to BBA (Computer Application).

CGPA: 9.04Percent: 84.83%Grade: A+

## HSC (12th) Maharashtra Board

Moledina High School & jr College Mar 2018 - Feb 2019

percent: -54.15%

### **LANGUAGES**

English

Hindi

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$ 

Marathi

• • • • •

AWARDS

## **IIT Bombay**

• Certificate for completion of LibreOffice

# Abeda Inamdar Senior College

• 4th Rank in Blind Coding (C programming) at college fest